Guide to the International Union of Bricklayers and Allied Craftworkers, Local 7, Tile Marble & Terrazzo Records WAG.185
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
International Union of Bricklayers and Allied Craftworkers, Local 7, Tile Marble & Terrazzo Records
circa 1945-1999
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
International Union of Bricklayers and Allied Craftsmen. Local 7 (New York and New Jersey)
WAG.185
9.25 Linear Feet in 9 record cartons, 1 manuscript box, and 1 shared box.
Local 7 of the International Union of Bricklayers and Allied Craftsmen was formed on November 1, 1994 by the merger of seven individual unions from New Jersey and the greater New York City metropolitan area. The collection contains minutes, correspondence, contracts, financial records, election results, photographs, and ephemera.
Arrangement
Collection is arranged into two series, Series I. Records and Series II. Photographs and Ephemera. Materials in Series I: Records are arranged in original order. Materials in Series II: Photographs and Ephemera are arranged alphabetically.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by the International Union of Bricklayers and Allied Craftsmen, Local 7, in 1998 and 2002. The accession numbers associated with this gift are 1950.052, 2000.019, and 2000.020.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Historical Note
Local 7 of the International Union of Bricklayers and Allied Craftsmen was formed on November 1, 1994 by the merger of seven individual unions including the Tile Setters Union of NY & NJ (formally Local 52), the Tile Finishers of NY (formally Local 88), Tile Finishers of NJ (formally Local 77), Marble Carvers, Cutters, & Setters Union of NY & NJ (formally Local 4), Marble Finishers Union of NY (formally Local 20), Marble Polishers & Restoration Finishers of NY (formally Local 24), Terrazzo, Mosaic, & Decorative Chemical Product Finishers (formally Local 3). The union's geographic jurisdiction encompasses all of state of New Jersey, all Boroughs of Greater New York City, all of Long Island, and the counties of Westchester, Rockland, Sullivan, Ulster, Dutchess, Putnam, and Orange.
Scope and Content Note
The International Union of Bricklayers and Allied Craftworkers, Local 7, Tile Marble & Terrazzo Records (dated circa 1945-1999) contain the organizational records and photographs of the International Union of Bricklayers and Allied Craftworkers, Local 7. Materials in this collection relate to several local unions that eventually incorporated to from Local 7 in 1994. The bulk of the records relate to the Tile Finishers of New York (formerly Local 88 of the International Union of Bricklayers and Allied Craftsmen). These materials include election records, executive board minutes, correspondence, receipt books, and membership application forms. Materials related to other locals include contracts and bylaws from Local 24, and membership cards from Local 10. Graphic materials in this collection include black and white photographs and portraits of union officials and politicians. They also include one ULLICO (the Union Labor Life Insurance Company) ruler and five different brochures, pamphlets, and flyers.
Custodial History
The archived website was migrated from the California Digital Library's Web Archiving Service to the Internet Archive's Archive-It Service in November 2015. The link to California Digital Library was removed in October 2017.
Labor movement -- New York (State); Photographs.; Minutes (administrative records); Correspondence.; Contracts; Election returns.; Building trades -- New York (State) -- New York; International Union of Bricklayers and Allied Craftsmen. Local 7 (New York and New Jersey); International Union of Bricklayers and Allied Craftsmen. Local 7 (New York and New Jersey)
- Series I: Records, 1946-1989
  Scope and Contents
  Series I: Records contains the organizational records of International Union of Bricklayers and Allied Craftworkers, Local 7, Tile Marble & Terrazzo. The series includes minutes, correspondence, contracts, financial records, election results, photographs, and ephemera. A large portion of these records are from the Tile Finishers of New York (formerly Local 88 of the International Union of Bricklayers and Allied Craftsmen).
  - Local 88: Minutes, 1946-1970 (Box 1)
  - Local 88: Correspondence, 1955-1970 (Box 1)
  - Local 24: Contracts, undated (Box 2)
  - Local 88: Minutes, 1968 (Box 2)
  - Local 88: Receipt Books, 1946-1966 (Box 3)
  - Local 88: Correspondence, 1955-1962 (Box 3)
  - Local 88: Correspondence and Contracts, 1946-1980 (Box 4)
  - Local 88: Contract Changes, 1957 (Box 5)
  - Local 88: Financial Records and Minutes, 1948 (Box 5)
  - Local 88: Correspondence with International Union, 1961-1987 (Box 5, Box 6)
  - Local 88: Correspondence, 1969-1985 (Box 7)
  - Local 88: Election Results, 1950-1989 (Box 7, Box 6)
  - Local 88: Executive Board Election, 1987 (Box 7)
  - Local 10: Membership Cards, undated (Box 8)
  - Local 88: Apprentice Files, 1986-1988 (Box 7, Box 9)
  - Local 88: Executive Board Minutes, 1946-1981 (Box 9)
- Series II: Photographs and Ephemera, circa 1945-1999
  Scope and Content Note
  Series II: Photographs and Ephemera includes black and white photographs including portraits of union officials and politicians. Also includes one ULLICO (the Union Labor Life Insurance Company) ruler and five different brochures (pamphlets/flyers) from B.A.C. Local 7.
  - Bricklayers and Allied Craftworkers Publications, 1999, undated (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Brooklyn Board of Business Agents A.F. of L. Annual Luncheon, Feb 1950 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Brooklyn Board of Business Agents A.F. of L. Annual Luncheon, Feb 1951 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Group Portrait, circa 1945-1965 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Group Portraits, 1947, undated (Box Shared Tamiment OS002)
  - Important Information Regarding your Membership with the International Union of Bricklayers and Allied Craftworkers, 1998 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - International Masonry Institute: If You Can Imagine It, We Can Bring It to Life, 1998 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - John Powers, President of Local 4, with Ronald Reagan, 1982 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Malcom Cohen Bust, 1999 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Marble Carvers, Cutters, and Setters Union Local 4, circa 1945-1960 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Pictures for Labor Day City Hall Local Archives, circa 1940-1960 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Union Labor Life Insurance Company Ruler, undated (Box 10, Folder 11)
- Series III: Archived Website, May 3, 2009-ongoing
  Founded in 1865, the International Union of Bricklayers and Allied Craftworkers represents craftworkers in the trowel trades across the United States and Canada including bricklayers, stone and marble masons, cement masons, plasterers, tilesetters, terrazzo and mosaic workers, and pointers/cleaners/caulkers. The website contains contracts, training and organizing programs, benefit programs, and event listings.
  Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
  Due to technical or privacy issues, archived websites may not be exact copies of the original website at the time of the web crawl. Certain file types will not be captured dependent on how they are embedded in the site. Other parts of websites that the crawler has difficulty capturing includes Javascript, streaming content, database-driven content, and highly interactive content. Full-Text searches of archived websites are available at https://archive-it.org/organizations/567.